Hello, my name is David Brown and this is a pronunciation class.
大家好，我叫戴维·布朗，这是一堂发音课。
Hi, welcome. How are you?
你好，欢迎。你怎么样？
Hello, thank you. I'm doing well. And you?
你好，谢谢。我很好。您呢？
I'm doing great. Thank you. What's your name?
我非常好。谢谢。你叫什么名字？
My name is Lourdes. Lourdes Landa.
我叫洛德斯 (Luòdésī)。洛德斯·兰达。
Hi, Ms. Lourdes. Welcome. I'm Mr. Brown. Where are you from?
你好，洛德斯女士。欢迎。我是布朗先生。你来自哪里？
I'm from Tegucigalpa Honduras.
我来自洪都拉斯特古西加尔巴。
Okay, Tegucigalpa. Awesome. My wife is from Tegucigalpa.
好的，特古西加尔巴。太棒了。我的妻子来自特古西加尔巴。
Oh, that's nice.
哦，那太好了。
Yeah, nice to meet you.
是的，很高兴认识你。
Nice to meet you, too.
我也很高兴认识您。
I see that you selected a lesson about these different TH sounds. Is that okay?
我看到您选择了一节关于这些不同 TH 音的课程。可以吗？
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
Okay, we have two sounds that can be tricky. We have the TH sound that is voiceless and the TH sound, which is voiced.
好的，我们有两个可能比较棘手的音。我们有不发声的 TH 音和发声的 TH 音。
Both involve putting your tongue between your teeth.
两者都涉及到把你的舌头放在牙齿之间。
One, the voiced one has a vibration and the voiceless one does not have a vibration.
其中一个，发声的那个有振动，而不发声的那个没有振动。
We need to know when to use this and when to remember how to use these different sounds here.
我们需要知道什么时候使用这个，以及什么时候记住如何使用这些不同的音。
So we'll start. So a question. Have you ever said is sync when you meant to say think or free instead of three?
那么我们开始吧。一个问题。你有没有在想说 think 的时候说成 sync，或者想说 three 的时候说成 free？
I think I've done that before you.
我想我以前这样做过。
And it's pretty common. Even some native speakers, some native speakers, for example, will say birth day with an F instead of a TH sound.
这很常见。甚至一些母语者，例如，有些母语者会说 birth day 时用 F 音代替 TH 音。
A little bit of practice. You know where to put your tongue. If you know what sound it makes where the sounds come from.
稍加练习。你知道舌头应该放在哪里。如果你知道它发出什么音，这些音从哪里来。
It can easily be fixed. You can learn to hear and produce these differences and sounds.
这很容易就能纠正。你可以学会听辨和发出这些不同的音。
Okay.
好的。
So here are some objectives. I'd like for you to read these.
这里有一些目标。我希望你读一下这些。
Well, I want you to listen to these objectives here. So we're going to be able to distinguish between these T8 sounds. We have the voiceless and the voiced fricatives.
嗯，我希望你们听一下这里的这些目标。所以我们将能够区分这些 TH 音。我们有清摩擦音和浊摩擦音。
We're going to describe and demonstrate the correct mouth movements mechanics for these different sounds.
我们将描述并演示发出这些不同音的正确口部动作机制。
I will be able to produce these accurately in isolated words and also in short phrases as well. So we'll try to use them in context.
我将能够准确地在单个词语中以及短语中发出这些音。所以我们将尝试在语境中使用它们。
And we'll try to recognize and come and spelling patterns associated with TH.
并且我们将尝试识别与 TH 相关的常见拼写模式。
And you need to basically notice and correct yourself whenever you use TH and practice.
你基本上需要在每次使用 TH 时注意并自我纠正，然后练习。
So it's some fine tuning for pronunciation in today's class.
所以今天的课是对发音进行一些微调。
How do you feel about your pronunciation? Do you feel like you need to work on your pronunciation?
你对自己的发音感觉如何？你觉得你需要练习发音吗？
Yes, definitely.
是的，当然。
Okay. I think this is a good class even for some of us native speakers to as well. So no worries if you feel nervous. It's completely normal.
好的。我认为这堂课即使对我们一些母语者来说也很好。所以如果你感到紧张，不用担心。这完全正常。
And don't feel afraid to be silly. It's a pretty silly class when you're making weird sounds with your tongue and teeth.
并且不要害怕显得傻气。当你用舌头和牙齿发出奇怪的声音时，这堂课会很有趣。
Thank you.
谢谢。
That improving this can help you in your daily conversations or at work. By the way, Lord, what do you do? What is your job?
改进这一点可以帮助你的日常对话或工作。顺便问一下，洛德斯，你是做什么工作的？你的职业是什么？
I actually work with the government.
我实际上在政府部门工作。
The legal department in an office.
在一个办公室的法律部门。
And there's just a few people that can actually speak English. So when something like that comes near my help.
而且实际上只有少数几个人会说英语。所以当类似的事情发生时，他们需要我的帮助。
And I think that is going to be very useful if I know the proper way to pronounce these kind of words because it gets confused.
而且我认为如果我知道如何正确发这些词的音，那会非常有用，因为很容易混淆。
Okay, definitely. So you have a good reason to practice this today and to improve your pronunciation.
好的，当然。所以你今天有充分的理由来练习并改进你的发音。
We need to understand these two different sounds and what voiceless and voiced means because well, anytime we talk, we can feel vibrations or not.
我们需要理解这两个不同的音，以及清音和浊音意味着什么，因为，嗯，任何时候我们说话，我们都能感觉到振动或者感觉不到。
So if you put your hands in front of your throat here, if you can do that for me.
所以如果你把手放在喉咙前面这里，你能为我这样做吗。
And just start talking. Say something. Maybe a phrase.
然后开始说话。说点什么。也许一个短语。
Hello, my name is Noah. Hi. Yes, I can definitely feel that.
你好，我叫诺亚。你好。是的，我确实能感觉到。
So you see that there are moments when it vibrates and moments when it doesn't vibrate.
所以你看到有些时候它会振动，有些时候它不会振动。
Essentially, these voiced sounds with ED at the end voiced are vowel sounds that will find in different parts of the word.
基本上，这些浊音与元音的发声方式有关，我们会在词语的不同部分找到它们。
These are voiced sounds. And the ones, the sounds that we make that don't vibrate here are the voiceless ones.
这些是浊音。而那些我们发出的、在这里不振动的音，是清音。
So we see in the chart that we have two different examples, one for the voiceless thick.
所以我们在图表中看到两个不同的例子，一个是清音的 thick。
And there's no vibration. So if you put your hand here, if you put your hand here for me and say, thick,
并且没有振动。所以如果你把手放在这里，为我把手放在这里然后说，thick，
thick, you shouldn't, you shouldn't feel any vibration at all for that one, right?
thick，你根本不应该感觉到任何振动，对吧？
Again, thick, no vibration. Maybe for the, yes, but for the TH, no, right?
再说一遍，thick，没有振动。也许对于，是的，但是对于 TH，没有，对吧？
Now, this next one, please, you try again, even the tongue vibrates, right?
现在，下一个，请你再试一次，甚至舌头也会振动，对吧？
So if vibrates, yeah, all the way up, this vibration and the vocal track continues onward,
所以如果振动，是的，一直向上，这种振动和声道会继续向前，
and we have this voice sound with these. So we have the voice sound with TH and with this vowel sound here.
我们用这些发出浊音。所以我们用 TH 和这里的元音发出浊音。
So a certain consonants can also come along with different types of voice sounds too, like these voiced fricatives.
所以某些辅音也可能伴随着不同类型的浊音，比如这些浊摩擦音。
So this is the sound in words like, think with no vibration, right?
所以这是像 think 这样的词中的音，没有振动，对吧？
Thank, then, back, path and three.
Thank, then, back, path 和 three.
Thank.
Thank.
Now, make sure that your tongue goes between your teeth. Can you read this part for us here?
现在，确保你的舌头在牙齿之间。你能为我们读一下这部分吗？
Think, think, think, think, back, three.
Think, think, think, think, back, three.
Okay, good. So notice that these don't vibrate.
好的，很好。所以注意这些音不振动。
So we don't want to confuse these and say, think, for example, the sounds more like a dip sound.
所以我们不想混淆这些，比如说 think，这个音听起来更像一个 dip 音。
We don't want to use voice fricatives when we're not supposed to and vice versa.
我们不应该在不该用的时候用浊摩擦音，反之亦然。
So it takes some memory and some vibration here.
所以这需要一些记忆和一些这里的振动。
So we practice the TH sound here. Remember, you should feel no buzz there.
所以我们在这里练习 TH 音。记住，你不应该感觉到那里的嗡嗡声。
Let's try this again. We'll try the, and the, the, for the sound, you can feel a little bit of air on your hand.
让我们再试一次。我们将尝试，和，那个，对于这个音，你可以在手上感觉到一点气流。
Can you say,
你能说，
I guess the, uh, at the end is a bit.
我想，呃，结尾有点。
What the, uh, I think, what the TH sound there is not voiced.
那个，呃，我想，那里的 TH 音不是浊音。
It's a subtle difference, but an important one for pronunciation.
这是一个细微的差别，但对于发音来说很重要。
So we can see some differences between these.
所以我们可以看到这些之间的一些区别。
Essentially, they only difference.
基本上，它们唯一的区别。
You have the tongue between both, uh, tongue between your teeth and both of these pictures.
在这两张图片中，你的舌头都在牙齿之间，呃，舌头在牙齿之间。
But for the voiced fricative, you also have that vibration.
但是对于浊摩擦音，你还有那种振动。
Alright, so I think I've explained that and you understand, right?
好的，所以我想我已经解释清楚了，你也理解了，对吧？
This is the sound in words like now we have the buzz.
这是现在带有嗡嗡声的词语中的音。
I think I do. I know I have to practice.
我想我明白了。我知道我必须练习。
So we have the buzz sound in these words. So listen to me say it once.
所以这些词里有嗡嗡声。那么听我说一遍。
We have this. So you have a vibration.
我们有 this。所以你有振动。
This, that, then, mother, breathe, and they, you try.
This, that, then, mother, breathe, 还有 they, 你试试。
Okay, let's see.
好的，让我们看看。
Breathe, that, then, mother, breath, they.
Breathe, that, then, mother, breath, they.
Good. This one here. Breathe, breathe, breathe, breathe.
很好。这个。Breathe, breathe, breathe, breathe.
Good. Breathe.
很好。Breathe.
Huh? So notice that vibration there should be like a sound, like a buzz.
嗯？所以注意那里的振动应该像一个声音，像嗡嗡声。
Breathe. Good.
Breathe. 很好。
Much better.
好多了。
I think you see fear to make the other sound.
我想你害怕发出另一个音。
Another example of some sounds that have a voiced one will be like the letter S.
另一个带有浊音的例子是字母 S。
Sometimes it makes a sound too, versus that sound, which is voiceless.
有时它也会发出声音，与那个清音相对。
So the only difference there.
所以这是那里唯一的区别。